{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Enzyme-driven metabolic pathways can be made more efficient by", "opta": "concentrating enzymes within specific cellular compartments", "optb": "grouping enzymes into free-floating, multienzyme complexes", "optc": "fixing enzymes into membranes so that they are adjacent to each other", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following (s) is/are serine proteases?", "opta": "Chymotrypsin", "optb": "Trypsin", "optc": "Elastase", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements about enzymes or their function is true?", "opta": "Enzymes do not alter the overall change in free energy for a reaction", "optb": "Enzymes are proteins whose three-dimensional form is key to their function", "optc": "Enzymes speed up reactions by lowering activation energy", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Tryprotophan synthetase of E.coli, a typical bifunctional oligomeric enzyme consist of", "opta": "a protein designated A", "optb": "two proteins designated A and B", "optc": "a protein A and one-subunit a", "optd": "a protein designated B", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the specificity of the Clostripain protease?", "opta": "It cleave after Arg residues", "optb": "It cleave after His residues", "optc": "It cleave after Lys residues", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The proteolysis rate enhancement by chymotrypsin (~1010 folds) corresponds to a reduction in activation energy of about", "opta": "40 kJ/mol", "optb": "49 kJ/mol", "optc": "58 kJ/mol", "optd": "88 kJ/mol", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is false statement with regard to comparison between Serine and HIV proteases?", "opta": "Both use nucleophilic attack to hydrolyze the peptide bond", "optb": "Both require water to complete the catalytic cycle", "optc": "Both forms an acyl-enzyme intermediate", "optd": "Both show specificity for certain amino acid sequences", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the enzyme-catalyzed reaction shown below, what will be the effect on substances A, B, C, and D of inactivating the enzyme labeled E2?  A ---(E1)---> B ---(E2)---> C ---(E3)--->", "opta": "A, B, C, and D will all still be produced", "optb": "A, B, and C will still be produced, but not D", "optc": "A and B will still be produced, but not C or D", "optd": "A will still be produced, but not B, C, or D", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The nucleophile in serine proteases is", "opta": "Serine", "optb": "water", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Asparagine", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The role of Asp 102 and His 57 during trypsin catalysis is to", "opta": "neutralize the charge on the other's side chain", "optb": "keep the specificity pocket open", "optc": "function as a proton shuttle", "optd": "clamp the substrate into the active site", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cleavage specificity of trypsin and chymotrypsin depend in part on the", "opta": "proximity of Ser 195 to the active site or specificity pocket", "optb": "size, shape, and charge of the active site or specificity pocket", "optc": "presence of a low-barrier hydrogen bond in the active site or specificity pocket", "optd": "absence of water in the active site", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The E.coli pyruvic acid dehydrogenase complex is reported to", "opta": "decatalyze the oxidation of pyruvic acid to acetyl Co A and CO2", "optb": "Catalyze the oxidation of pyruvic acid to acetyl Co A and CO2", "optc": "retard the reduction of pyruvic acid to acetyl Co A and CO2", "optd": "Catalyze the reduction of pyruvic acid to acetyl Co A and CO2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the common features are shared between serine and aspartate proteases?", "opta": "Both require water to complete the catalytic cycle", "optb": "Both use a base to activate the nucleophile", "optc": "Both show specificity for certain amino acid sequences", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Before they can react, many molecules need to be destabilized. This state is typically achieved through", "opta": "changing the three-dimensional shape of the molecule", "optb": "oxidizing the molecules by removing electrons", "optc": "changing the reaction from a biosynthetic to a catabolic pathway", "optd": "the input of a small amount of activation energy", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Common feature in all serine proteases is a", "opta": "hydrophobic specificity pocket", "optb": "hydrophilic specificity pocket", "optc": "cluster of reactive serine residues", "optd": "single reactive serine residue", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is the enzyme COX-1 important in human health?", "opta": "It helps to transport carbon dioxide in the blood", "optb": "It is critical for the biosynthesis of DNA", "optc": "It is a chemical derivative of aspirin", "optd": "It catalyzes the production of hormones that maintain the stomach lining", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}